SUJEET KUMAR

226-975-2285 • kumar31@uwindsor.ca • https://www.linkedin.com/in/sujeet-kumar18/ • https://www.sujeetkumar.ca

PROFILE

I am a hands-on operator and field leader with 3+ years of experience managing high-performing teams at Walmart and in plant environments. I sought to use my skillset to simplify and optimise processes, improve operational performance, implement change, and manage day-to-day operations with ownership and reliability. In my past and current role, I have been trusted to lead the implementation of strategic initiatives due to my sound judgement, ability to deal with ambiguity, and influence change in the teams I collaborate with.

EXPERIENCE

Walmart Canada

Manager | E-Comm Operations (store-fulfilled)

Feb 2022 – Present

- Responsible for all store-fulfilled E-Comm sales, leading a team of 25 associates, including pickers, dispensers.
- Optimized on-hands inventory for top 25 products by reducing nil-pick rate from 45% to 15%, thereby increasing store's E-Comm sales by 25% YoY to achieve ~\$3.5M in total GMV.
- Acted as liaison between Store Support Centre (Corporate), store associates, and customers; provided feedback on E-Comm operations and customer experience that helped improve CSAT scores across Mississauga market.
- Selected by Corporate as the main on-field POC for launching a strategic home delivery pilot program (reference avail. below) and uplifted home delivery orders from 0 to 120 WTD.
- Implemented <2H delivery offering (Express), providing operational support and feedback to maintain on-time delivery of 95%.
- Designed new SOP to pre-process order substitutes for customers picking up, increasing store NPS by 5 pts in 3 months.
- Optimized backroom activities and staff roles to dispense delivery orders faster, reducing pickup wait time from 15 to 5 mins by data visualization on Tableau.

Lucky Industries, Pakistan

Continuous Improvement Engineer

Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

- Conducted time & motion studies to identify 2-3 process improvements that yielded a 35% increase in output for the gear production line: applied LSS principles including Ishikawa, 5-Why for root cause, and Pareto for prioritizing recommendations.
- Implemented a quality control program by re-defining process control limits to reduce parts defects by 20% in 6 months, thereby reducing OpEx and increasing customer retention with fewer rejected/returned batches.
- Led cross-functional teams to implement a dock-yard management system, reducing trailer queues by 20 mins and reducing shunting required.
- Developed and implemented training programs for employees on Lean Manufacturing principles and techniques, resulting in a more engaged and knowledgeable workforce, with a 25% reduction in process waste.
- Implemented Health & Safety standards to reduce plant downtime and achieve the longest streak of zero shop incidents.

EDUCATION

University of Windsor Master of Mechanical Engineering Jan 2020 – Apr 2021

Technical Skills: MATLAB, Minitab, PowerBI (user), Tableau (user), Excel, PowerPoint, SolidWorks, AutoCAD

Certifications: Certified Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, Process Improvement, Project Management

Training: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, Power BI, Tableau, SQL & Data Visualization, HTML, CSS, JS

Reference: Taha Mirza, Senior Manager – Walmart Last Mile Delivery

Pawiterjit Rattan, Store Manager - Walmart